Gabriel Cuadros Caceres

Age: 30-year-old Day of Birth: 3 June 1989

Telephone: (+51) 999356628 DNI: 70490014

Email: gabrielcuadros@gmail.com

Nationality: Peruvian Passport: 118061791



DEVOPS INFRAESTRUCTURE AND DEVELOPER ENGINEER

Electronic engineer from Peru with 5 years of experience in the development of telecommunications and engineering projects with a desire to work as an engineer around the world, I have high level knowledge in automation, provisioning, configuration, hosting, monitoring and delivery of products such as Kubernetes, Docker, Vagrant, Mesos, Ansible, Terraform, Jenkins, , Maven and Opsview . I have used several programming languages during my work as Python, C #, Java, Ruby, Groovy, I have also managed several databases such as Mongodb, Elasticsearch and MySQL. Within the software development I have been able to work with REST API, CI / CD pipelines, error handling, unit testing, integration testing, deployment and troubleshooting of runtime applications. I am a person with a lot of motivation to learn and I like to teach people what I learn day by day.

Motion Capture

- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LOxwsCOE1Xg
- Gesture recognition
 - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MAceGI-EZMk

Devops challenge (ansible Vagrant Kubernetes docker)

- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VqG XK4b1eA
- https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kjY-O4XWhUQ

Image recognition

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bp6KlC4wf4M

Jenkins Pipeline challenge

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LAS3bXHv1I0

Terraform ansible challenge

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eT1T6Zsyi1w

Education

Universidad Peruana de Ciencias Aplicadas (UPC) - Perú

Electronic engineer 2006 - 2012
--Pearson Vue - U.S.A

Cisco CCNA R&S CSCO13054915 2018
--Udemy

Kubernetes, de principiante a experto 2020
--Udemy

Docker, de principiante a experto 2020

Udemy

Jenkins, de principiante a experto

2020

Udemy

Ansible, Automatización de principiante a experto

2020

Technologic resume

Operating system

• Red Hat, CentOS, SUSE.

Configuration and provisioning tools

• , Terraform, Ansible.

CI/CD tools

• Maven, Jenkins.

Repositories management

Nexus, Linux Repositories, Docker registry.

Virtualization and Containerization tools

Apache Mesos, Kubernetes, docker, Vagrant.

Infrastructure tools

• GitHub, Gitlab, Citrix NetScaler, Opsview, Apache, Nginx, Squid.

Programing languages and platform

• C#, Python, Ruby, .NET, Bash scripting, Java, Groovy, Android Java, Nodejs, Angular, Express.

Databases knowledge

• MySQL, MongoDB, Elasticsearch.

Infrastructure services

DNS, DHCP, FTP, WWW, SMTP, NFS, SSL, Reverse- Forward Proxy, Redirect web server.

Professional Experience

TGESTIONA DEL PERU — LIMA, PERU

Telecommunication specialist, December 2013 to January 2015 (13 month)

- maintenance of network equipment such as switches and router (Cisco, Juniper, Huawei, Zte) on a physical and logical level
- communicate effectively to external and internal customers and route incidents to the corresponding level 2 areas quickly
- Remedy ticket system management

ACHIVEMENTS

• compliance with ticket SLA issues for business and residential customers

System engineer, January 2015 to June 2016 (18 month)

- development of web and app tools for data scrapping with node.js, opencv.js, robot.js
- Linux server administration and Mesos datacenters
- REST API endpoint creation with node.JS, express.js, Mongodb
- Source control management with GitHub and Gitlab private environment
- Network service administration
- SQL and NOSQL Database administration
- Webpage creation with MVC with ruby on Rails, spring boot maven or Node.js + Angular.
- development of Android application

ACHIVEMENTS

- Streamline and modernize legacy Telefónica web pages with zero costs
- automate routine tasks in various areas of the company
- Transform information to improve visualization of head management
- development of tools that automatically interact with network equipment
- communicate Telefónica's Remedy ticket system with an Android application

AYNITECH-LIMA, PERU

System engineer, February 2017 to October 2017 (8 month)

- management of private repositories Linux, Docker, and Maven
- provisioning and configuration of physical and virtual servers with Openstack ,Terraform, Puppet
- Network service administration
- administration of the Netscaler citrix traffic balancer
- Opsview monitoring tool management
- Linux server administration
- node.js, Maven application troubleshooting
- development of node.js and Maven applications
- CI / CD streams with GitHub, Jenkins, Docker

ACHIVEMENTS

- Compliance in application deployment and support during and after deployment
- reduced service deployment times
- automation of routine tasks in the company
- bug fixes in the monitoring platform, as well as in the provisioning platform
- support and troubleshooting in the deployment of projects in Maven and node.js

ZTE CORPORATION – LIMA PERU

Applications engineer, February 2018 to August 2019 (18 month)

- deployment and maintenance for applications for mobile networks 4g, 3g
- development of node.js and Maven applications for automation and monitoring
- management of monitoring tools ELK, Prometheus, Grafana
- Linux server administration
- Database administration (oracle, Mongodb, Elasticsearch)
- CI / CD streams with GitHub, Jenkins, Docker tools.

ACHIVEMENTS

- downtime reduction in VAS service deployment and maintenance for Telefonica, Bitel, Entel
- automation of routine tasks in the company
- compliance with ticket SLA for new services and issues
- implementation of a CI / CD environment for local development during the ZTE ban export
- reduction in software maintenance and local software production times